Guide to the Boswell Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Manuscripts, 1755-1795; Series IV; 4.25; (11 boxes)
  - (including Tinker 298) (Box 58, Folder 1234)
  - Verses
    - "October" (M 264), 1757? (Box 58, Folder 1235)
    - "October. A Poem" (M 265), 1757? (Box 58, Folder 1235)
    - "Prologue to The Coquettes " (M 266), 1758? (Box 58, Folder 1235)
    - "Ode on Miss Wells" (M 267), 1760 (Box 58, Folder 1235)
    - "Song by an Old Lord" (M 268), 1760-62? (Box 58, Folder 1236)
    - "Epitaph upon Mr. John Campbell" (M 268.2), 1761 (Box 58, Folder 1236)
    - "The Snake, a Song" (M 269), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1236)
    - "Song for a Showman" (M 270), 1762-63 (Box 58, Folder 1236)
    - "Johnston to whom each Tuesday goes" (M 271), 1762-63 (Box 58, Folder 1237)
    - "O Wilkes he is a rare dog" (M 272), 1762-63 (Box 58, Folder 1237)
    - "A Ludicrous Hodge-Podge" (M 273), 1763 (Box 58, Folder 1237)
    - A dialogue concerning Wilkes (M 274), 1763 (Box 58, Folder 1237)
    - "The Half-Pay Officer's Lamentation" (M 275), 1763 (Box 58, Folder 1238)
    - "Ten Lines a Day" (M 276), 1763-64 (Box 58, Folder 1238)
    - "To Flexney" (M 277), 1763? (Box 58, Folder 1239)
    - "Parliament. An Epistle" (M 278), 1764 (Box 58, Folder 1239)
    - "Parliament. A Poem" (M 279), 1764-65 (Box 58, Folder 1239)
    - "Lines on Melancholy" (M 279.1), 1765 (Box 58, Folder 1239)
    - "To G. L. Hertel" (M 280), 1764 (Box 59, Folder 1240)
    - "Ten Lines a Day" (M 281-282), 1764 (Box 59, Folder 1240)
    - Amyot: translation of (M 283), 1764 (Box 59, Folder 1240)
    - "Ten Lines a Day" (M 285), 1765 (Box 59, Folder 1241)
    - "To Alexandre Deleyre" (M 286), 1765 (Box 59, Folder 1241)
    - "Epistle to Wilkes" (M 287), 1765 (Box 59, Folder 1241)
    - "Spoken Extempore on hearing of a Young Lady's Marrying a Menial Servant" (M 288), 1765 (Box 59, Folder 1241)
    - "Song in the Character of Lord---" (M 289), 1766 (Box 59, Folder 1242)
    - "Vers en caractére de M. Rousseau" (M 290), 1766? (Box 59, Folder 1242)
    - "The Hamilton Cause" (M 291), 1767 (Box 59, Folder 1242)
    - "Ten Lines a Day" (M 293), n.d.;1769 (Box 59, Folder 1243)
    - "Epitaph upon an Amiable Deist" (M 294), 177-? (Box 59, Folder 1243)
    - "Ten Lines a Day" (M 296), 1774 (Box 59, Folder 1244)
    - "Ten Lines a Day" (M 297), 1778 (Box 59, Folder 1245)
    - "Upon the Caledonian Coast" (M 298), 1778 (Box 59, Folder 1245)
    - "Ten Lines a Day" (M 299), 1779 (Box 59, Folder 1245)
    - Verses written at Carlisle (M 300), 1779 (Box 59, Folder 1246)
    - "Ten Lines a Day" (M 301), 1780 (Box 59, Folder 1246)
    - "Ode by Dr. Samuel Johnson to Mrs.Thrale..." (M 302), 1781 (Box 59, Folder 1247)
    - "On Dr. Bancroft's Promotion..." (M 303), 1781 (Box 59, Folder 1247)
    - "Extempore in Gen. Paoli's Chariot" (M 304), 1781 (Box 59, Folder 1247)
    - "Distict made extempore" (M 305), 1781 (Box 59, Folder 1248)
    - "The Tears of Old Tyburn Tree" (M 306), 1783 (Box 59, Folder 1248)
    - "Soldier so jealous of thy Prince's fame" (M 308), 1784 (Box 59, Folder 1248)
    - "Sing those who may", 1786 (Box 59, Folder 1249)
    - "Lines supposed to be written by Mrs. Piozzi" (M 310), 1786 (Box 59, Folder 1249)
    - "Cantata" (M 311), n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1250)
    - "Hush Westminster Hall" (M 312), 1788? (Box 59, Folder 1250)
    - "I must have a hemisphere of Love" (M 313), 1790 (Box 59, Folder 1250)
    - "On Jack Courtenay" (M 314), 1790 (Box 59, Folder 1250)
    - Lines mentioning Courtenay (M 315), 1790? (Box 59, Folder 1251)
    - "Song for Carleton House" (M 316), 1790 (Box 59, Folder 1251)
    - "My Own Cousin Taddy" (M 317), n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1251)
    - "To Lady ___" (M 318), 1790? (Box 59, Folder 1251)
    - "Lancaster Politicks 1790" (M 319) (Box 59, Folder 1252)
    - "Epitaph on Mr. Ross" (M 320), 1790 (Box 59, Folder 1252)
    - "To Mr. Andrew Stuart" (M 321), 1790 (Box 59, Folder 1252)
    - "On a Temple of Cloacina" (M 322), 1790 (Box 59, Folder 1252)
    - William Pitt, the Grocer of London (M 323), 1790 (Box 59, Folder 1253)
    - "Epigram on a Bon Vivant" (M 324), 1790 (Box 59, Folder 1253)
    - "Ye Nuns and Carmelites begin the Song" (M 325), 1790? (Box 59, Folder 1253)
    - "No Abolition of Slavery" (M 326-327), 1791 (Box 59, Folder 1254)
    - "Let those who abhor all Kings and Priests" (M 328), 1791 (Box 59, Folder 1255)
    - "On William Gerald Hamilton" (M 329), 1792 (Box 59, Folder 1255)
    - "At shortning great names" (M 330), 1792 (Box 59, Folder 1255)
    - "On Benjamin West" (M 331), 1792 (Box 59, Folder 1255)
    - "The Centaur Not Fabulous" (M 332), 1792 (Box 59, Folder 1256)
    - "On...Mis Selena Eardley" (M 333), 1792 (Box 59, Folder 1256)
    - "Palmeria it seems will be wedded at last" (M 334), 1792 (Box 59, Folder 1256)
    - "Epithalamium" (M 335), 1792 (Box 59, Folder 1256)
    - "Bishop Barnard is't a sin, say" (M 336), 1792 (Box 59, Folder 1257)
    - "Fox's Opposition 1793" (M 337) (Box 59, Folder 1257)
    - "On hearing Lady Salisbury" (M 338), 1793 (Box 59, Folder 1257)
    - "On Observing a Lock of Miss Baldwin's Hair" (M 339), 1793 (Box 59, Folder 1257)
    - "...Ballochmiln to Ballamyle" (M 340), 1794? (Box 59, Folder 1258)
    - "On Benjamin West's Choice" (M 341), 1794 (Box 59, Folder 1258)
    - "Pathetick Song" (M 342), 1794 (Box 59, Folder 1258)
    - Miscellaneous incomplete or undated poems (M 343) (Box 59, Folder 1259)
    - Verses and songs copied by Boswell (M 344-351) (Box 59, Folder 1260)
  - "Woodside" (M 352), 1783 (Box 59, Folder 1261)
  - Wrappers labelled by Boswell (M 353), n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1262)
- Printed Material, 1647-1918; Series V; 2.25; (6 boxes)
  Boxes 60-65 hold Series V, Printed Material. The items are in a single alphabetical run. Works by James Boswell will be found under their titles. Other works are listed alphabetically by author if known, and by title, subject, or form if not. For more specific guidance, consult the galleys to the Catalogue.
  - Galleys (Box 60, Folder 1264)
  - Arnot, Hugh: A Letter to the Lord Advocate of Scotland (P 1), 1777 (Box 60, Folder 1265)
  - Association for Preserving Liberty (P 2) (Box 60, Folder 1265)
  - Auchinleck Press: engraving (P 3), 1817 (Box 60, Folder 1265)
  - Auld Reekie--1785 (P 4) (Box 60, Folder 1266)
  - Ayr: Order of the Grand Procession of King Crispin (P 5), 1821 (Box 60, Folder 1266)
  - Ayrshire: Address to the Prince of Wales (P 6)
  - The Barber. A New Song (Box 60, Folder 1267)
  - Bembo, Pietro: Epistolas familiares fragment (P 8), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1267)
  - Bibliotheca Boswelliana (P 9), 1825 (Box 60, Folder 1268)
  - Bickerstaffe, Isaac: The Padlock. A Comic Opera (P 10), [1768?] (Box 60, Folder 1269)
  - Boswell, Sir Alexander
    - Excellent Auld Song (P 11), [1797?] (Box 60, Folder 1270)
    - Loch-side and Dam-back (P 12) (Box 60, Folder 1270)
    - Songs (P 13), 1802 (Box 60, Folder 1270)
    - Sir Albon (P 14), [1808] (Box 60, Folder 1270)
    - Catalogue of Greek and Latin Classics... (P 15), 1810 (Box 60, Folder 1271)
    - Song (P 16), 1815 (Box 60, Folder 1272)
    - Yes! Tears Must Flow (P 17), 1815 (Box 60, Folder 1272)
    - Clan-Alpin's Vow (P 18), 1817 (Box 60, Folder 1272)
    - "Answer" (P 19), 1820 (Box 60, Folder 1273)
    - Long Live George the Fourth (P 20), 1821 (Box 60, Folder 1273)
    - Lines...on the Death of his Brother (Box 60, Folder 1273)
      - (P 21), [1822] (Box 60, Folder 1273)
  - Boswell, James, the younger
    - Reply signed "Hospitalis," St. James Chronicle (P 22), 1792 (Box 60, Folder 1274)
    - A Bibliographical Memoir...of Malone (P 23), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1274)
  - [Boswell, Robert]: Proposals for... a Scheme of Annuities (P 24), 1772 (Box 60, Folder 1275)
  - Boswell, Veronica: watercolor of two flowers (P 25), 1783 (Box 60, Folder 1275)
  - Boswell family: coat of arms, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1275)
  - Botany Bay: "Leaves from Botany Bay used as Tea" (P 27), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1276)
  - Carlisle by-election: papers (P 28-29), 1786 (Box 60, Folder 1277-78)
  - A Catalogue of...Books of...Samuel Johnson (P 30), 1785 (Box 60, Folder 1279)
  - "Christianus" [William Grove]: On the death of Henrietta.... (P 31), 1793 (Box 61, Folder 1280)
  - "Copy of a Letter from J-- B--" (P 32)
  - Cornwall County Library: Resolutions (P 33) Rules and Observations (P 34)
  - Corsica
    - Supplement aux.... (P 35), 1767 (Box 61, Folder 1281)
    - Ribbon commemorating Paoli's return to Corsica (P 36), 1790 (Box 61, Folder 1281)
    - Discours prononcé...par le Générale Paoli (P 37), 1790 (Box 61, Folder 1281)
    - A' Corsi liberi, e Francesi (P 38) (Box 61, Folder 1282)
    - Ai Corsi liberi, e Francesi (P 39), 1793 (Box 61, Folder 1282)
    - Aux Corses libres et Français (P 40), 1793 (Box 61, Folder 1282)
    - Lettre écrite par le Conseil Général (P 41), 1793 (Box 61, Folder 1283)
    - Lettre...aux Administrateurs des Départemens (P 42), [1793] (Box 61, Folder 1283)
  - [Courtenay, John]: Englands Triumph (P 43), [c.1790] (Box 61, Folder 1294)
  - Cowper, William: Song, to the Tune of: (P 44), [179-] (Box 61, Folder 1294)
  - [Crowe, William]: New College Chapel (P 45), [1785?] (Box 61, Folder 1294)
  - Dance, George, the Younger: portrait of James Boswell (P 46), 1808 (Box 61, Folder 1285)
  - Disquisitio de mutuo (P 47), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1285)
  - Drummond, William: Polemo-Middinia (P 48) (Box 61, Folder 1285)
  - Dun, John: Proposals for Printing... two Volumes of Sermons (P 49), 1781 (Box 61, Folder 1286)
  - Edinburgh Advertiser: proof (P 50) (Box 61, Folder 1286)
  - The English Barrister to his Mistress (P 51) (Box 61, Folder 1286)
  - Erskine, Andrew: playbill (P 52) (Box 61, Folder 1286)
  - Etching: Madonna and Child (P 53) (Box 61, Folder 1286)
  - An Excellent New War-Song (Box 61, Folder 1287)
  - The Faculty Garland (P 55), [1785?] (Box 61, Folder 1287)
  - Fitzgerald, William Thomas: The Republican's Picture (P 56), 179[2] (Box 61, Folder 1287)
  - Foulis, Robert and Andrew (P 57)
  - Genoa: Balbi Palace (P 58), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1288)
  - Germany: An Accurate Map (P 59), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1288)
  - Green, Richard: portrait (P 59.1), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1288)
  - Hertell, Georg Ludwig: Brunsvic's First Celebration (P 60), [1764] (Box 61, Folder 1289)
  - Humane Society: advertisement (P 61), 1792 (Box 61, Folder 1289)
  - Hume, David: engraved portrait (P 62), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1289)
  - The Hypochondriack (Box 61, Folder 1289)
    - Nos. I-LX (P 63), 1777-81 (Box 61, Folder 1290)
    - Nos. II-LXX (P 64), 1777-83 (Box 61, Folder 1291-94)
    - Nos. I-LXIX (P 65), 1777-85 (Box 62, Folder 1295-98)
  - "Impromptu, by Mr. Boswell" (P 66) (Box 62, Folder 1299)
  - James, W.: A Defence of Mr. Boswell's Journal (P 67), 1785 (Box 62, Folder 1299)
  - Jamieson, John: Proposals for... Printing the Life of King Robert Bruce (P 68), n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1299)
  - Johnson, Alexander: "Circular Letter" (P 69), [1792?] (Box 62, Folder 1299)
  - Johnson, Alexander (Box 62, Folder 1300)
    - Directions for Recovering Persons Apparently Dead (P 70), [1785?] (Box 62, Folder 1300)
    - Relief from Accidental Death (P 71-72), 1789,1790 (Box 62, Folder 1301)
  - Johnson, Samuel
    - The Convict's Address (P 73), 1777 (Box 62, Folder 1302)
    - Dictionary fragments (P 74), 1755 (Box 62, Folder 1302)
    - Dr. Dodd (P 75), [1777] (Box 62, Folder 1302)
    - Prologue to The Word to the Wise (P 76), 1777 (Box 62, Folder 1303)
    - Proposals for...the Works of Mrs.Charlotte Lennox (P 77), 1775 (Box 62, Folder 1303)
    - Proposals for Printing An Analysis of the Scotch-Celtic Language (P 78), 1777 (Box 62, Folder 1303)
  - Johnsoniana; or, A Collection of Bon Mots (P 79), 1777 (Box 62, Folder 1304)
  - Journal of a Tour to the Hebrides
    - volume missing (P 80) "Letter on my Tour" (P 81) (Box 62, Folder 1305)
    - Newspaper clippings (P 82), 1785 (Box 62, Folder 1306)
    - English Review (P 83), 1785 (Box 62, Folder 1307)
    - Proof sheets (P 84-86), 1785 (Box 63, Folder 1308-19)
  - Kassel, Library of the Landgrave (P 87) (Box 63, Folder 1320)
  - Lancaster by-election: papers, 1786 (Box 63, Folder 1320)
  - Lawrence, Sir Thomas: sketches of James Boswell (P 89-91), 1794-95 (Box 64, Folder 1321)
  - "A Letter from James Boswell, An Account of the Armed Corsican Chief" London Magazine, 1769 (Box 64, Folder 1322)
  - A Letter...on the Present State of the Nation (P 93), 1784 (Box 64, Folder 1322)
  - A Letter to the People of Scotland: proof sheets (P 94), 1785 (Box 64, Folder 1323)
  - "Letter to the Printer" (P 95)
  - "Letter to the Printer" (P 96)
  - Letters between...Andrew Erskine and James Boswell, Esq.: reviews (P 97-98), 1763 (Box 64, Folder 1323)
  - Life of Samuel Johnson
    - Advertisements (P 99), 1787 (Box 64, Folder 1324)
    - "Paragraphs relative to..." (P 100), c.1790 (Box 64, Folder 1324)
    - Miscellaneous news articles (P 101), 1786-92 (Box 64, Folder 1325)
    - Passage from advertisement (P 102), n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1326)
    - Title proofs and corrected sheet (Box 64, Folder 1326)
      - (P 103), 1789 (Box 64, Folder 1326)
  - London Sportsmen (P 104) (Box 64, Folder 1327)
  - Malone, Edmond: Plays and Poems of Shakespeare (P 105), 1813 (Box 64, Folder 1327)
  - Mariottini, Felix: Proposals... (P 106), 1793 (Box 64, Folder 1327)
  - Merry, J.: Witticisms...of Johnson (P 107), 1791 (Box 64, Folder 1328)
  - Montgomerie family: Memorables of the Montgomeries (P 108), 1770 (Box 64, Folder 1329)
  - Motives grounded upon the Word of God....: fragment (P 109), 1647 (Box 64, Folder 1329)
  - Mundell, James: List of Scholars.... (P 110), 1789 (Box 64, Folder 1329)
  - Muratori, Lodovico: Novus thesaurus veterum inscriptionum (P 111), 1765 (Box 64, Folder 1330)
  - Murphy, Arthur: A Poetical Epistle (P 112), 1760 (Box 64, Folder 1330)
  - The Newsmans' Present (P 113), 1810,1814 (Box 64, Folder 1331)
  - Newspaper cuttings
    - "Newspaper paragraphs by myself, or relating to me" (P 114-118), 1766-93 (Box 64, Folder 1332-34)
    - "Newspapers, partly Johnsonian" (P 119-120), 1777-85 (Box 64, Folder 1335)
    - "Notices of my appearances" (P 121), 1790-92 (Box 64, Folder 1336)
    - "Publick Advertiser 1792-93" (P 122) (Box 64, Folder 1337)
    - "Publick Advertiser": miscellaneous clippings (P 123) "St. James's Chronicle 1792-93" (P 124) (Box 64, Folder 1337)
    - Miscellaneous clippings (P 125-126), 1778-1918 (Box 64, Folder 1338-39)
  - Nobli Sarelli, Giuseppe Ottavio: In Morte dell'Abate.... (P 127), 1782 (Box 65, Folder 1340)
  - Nominal and fictitious votes: Explanation of the Statutes.... (P 128) (Box 65, Folder 1340)
  - Notices: four announcements (P 129), 1786-92 (Box 65, Folder 1340)
  - "Notices...for lost articles" (P 130), [1788-89] (Box 65, Folder 1341)
  - Ode on Mr. Boswell's Going (P 131) (Box 65, Folder 1341)
  - Opinion of English Counsel...sent to Mr. Boswell (P 132), 1785 (Box 65, Folder 1341)
  - O'Rourke family (P 133)
  - Paoli, Pasquale de: engraved portrait (P 134), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1342)
  - Patterson, James: Contemporaries of Burns.... (P 135), [1840?] (Box 65, Folder 1342)
  - The Patriotic Chamberlain.... (P 136), 1776 (Box 65, Folder 1342)
  - Periodical clippings
    - Critical Memoirs of the Times (P 137), 1769 (Box 65, Folder 1343)
    - European Magazine (P 138-139), 1788,1792 (Box 65, Folder 1343)
    - Gentleman's Magazine (P 140-142), 1786-93 (Box 65, Folder 1344)
    - Weekly Entertainer (P 143), 1788 (Box 65, Folder 1344, Folder 1345)
    - Unidentified (P 144), [1792?] (Box 65, Folder 1344)
  - Pilkington: business card (P 145), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1346)
  - Playbills
    - Othello (P 146), 1758 (Box 65, Folder 1347)
    - The Beggar's Opera (P 147), 1758 (Box 65, Folder 1347)
    - The Earl of Essex (P 148), 1758 (Box 65, Folder 1347)
    - The Conscious Lovers (P 149), 1758 (Box 65, Folder 1347)
    - Which is the Man? (P 150), 1792 (Box 65, Folder 1347)
  - Proposals for...Shakespeare.Illustrated by Charlotte Lennox (P 151), 1793 (Box 65, Folder 1348)
  - "Rampager Essays" (P 152) (Box 65, Folder 1348)
  - Remarks upon...timber in Scotland (P 153), 1765 (Box 65, Folder 1348)
  - Rochester's Jests (P 154), 1758 (Box 65, Folder 1349)
  - Ross, David: Proposal for...the History of...the English Stage (P 155), 1790 (Box 65, Folder 1350)
  - Rousseau, Jean-Jacques: Receuil des ecrits....Prospectus, 1789 (Box 65, Folder 1350)
  - Engraved portrait (P 146-147), 1763 (Box 65, Folder 1350)
  - Schartow, Johanna Elisabeth: Der Demoiselle Schartow (P 148), 1764 (Box 65, Folder 1350)
  - Scott, William: portrait (P 159), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1351)
  - Song for the glorious 26th of June (P 160), 1792 (Box 65, Folder 1351)
  - Tanner, Bartholomew: A Discourse (P 161), 1764 (Box 65, Folder 1351)
  - The Thane of Bute.A New Song (P 162), 1762? (Box 65, Folder 1352)
  - Too True a Prophecy (P 163), 1788? (Box 65, Folder 1352)
  - Townshend of Raynham, George Townshend, 1st M.: On...Miss Gardiner (P 164), 1786 (Box 65, Folder 1352)
  - "Verax": Remarks on...a Tour (P 165), [1785] (Box 65, Folder 1353)
  - Voltaire, François Marie Arouet de: engraved portrait (P 166), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1353)
  - Water-colour drawing (P 167), [c.1751] (Box 65, Folder 1353)
  - Wilkes, John: Speech...to...Cornwallis (P 168), 1794 (Box 65, Folder 1354)
  - Speech...to...Meadows (P 169), 1794 (Box 65, Folder 1354)
  - William Pitt, the Grocer of London (P 170), 1790 (Box 65, Folder 1354)
- Legal Papers, 1735-1822; Series VI; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series VI, Legal Papers, is located in Boxes 66-68. It consists almost entirely of chronologically arranged material documenting the legal career of James Boswell.
  - Galleys (Box 66, Folder 1355)
  - Marriage contract: Geddes and Grant (Lg 1), [1735] (Box 66, Folder 1356)
  - Forrest and Sinclair: Petition (Lg 2), 1761? (Box 66, Folder 1356)
  - Joseph Taylor: Indictment (Lg 3), [1767] (Box 66, Folder 1357)
  - Information for Joseph Taylor (Lg 3), 1767 (Box 66, Folder 1357)
  - John Reid: Trial papers (Lg 4), 1766 (Box 66, Folder 1358)
  - Gabriel Stewart, John Robertson, et al.: Indictment (Lg 5), 1766 (Box 66, Folder 1359)
  - Court of Session cases (Lg 5.5), 1767-69 (Box 66, Folder 1359)
  - Robert Hay: papers (Lg 6.1), 1767 (Box 66, Folder 1360)
  - Copy of the Decree...to Mr. Eliot's Trust (Lg 7), 1767 (Box 66, Folder 1360)
  - Garliestown rioters: papers (Lg 8), 1767 (Box 66, Folder 1362)
  - Stewarton rioters: papers (Lg 9), 1767 (Box 66, Folder 1362)
  - Mackenzie v. Mackenzie: Information (Lg 10), 1767 (Box 66, Folder 1363)
  - George Dempster: papers (Lg 11), 1767-68 (Box 66, Folder 1364)
  - Unidentified case: page (Lg 12), n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1365)
  - Carruthers vs. Duke of Queensbury: Petition (Lg 13), 1768 (Box 66, Folder 1365)
  - James Archibald: papers (Lg 14), 1768 (Box 66, Folder 1366)
  - Petition of Margaret Brown (Lg 15), 1768? (Box 66, Folder 1366)
  - William Harris (or Harries)
    - Papers (Lg 16-17), 1768-69 (Box 66, Folder 1367)
    - Escape from Tolbooth (Lg 18), 1769 (Box 66, Folder 1368)
    - Proof in the Petition and Complaint (Box 66, Folder 1369)
      - (Lg 19.1), 1770 (Box 66, Folder 1369)
    - Papers (Lg 19.2-19.8), 1770 (Box 66, Folder 1370)
  - George MacDonald: papers (Lg 20), 1772 (Box 66, Folder 1371)
  - Court of Session cases (Lg 21), 1772-73 (Box 66, Folder 1372)
  - John Reid
    - Papers on the trial (Lg 22), 1774 (Box 66, Folder 1373)
    - Papers concerning the King's Mercy (Lg 23), 1774 (Box 66, Folder 1374)
    - Broadsides (Lg 24), 1774 (Box 66, Folder 1374)
  - Henry McGraugh: papers (Lg 25), 1774 (Box 67, Folder 1375)
  - William Robertson: note (Lg 26), 1775 (Box 67, Folder 1375)
  - Court of Session cases (Lg 27), 1775-76 (Box 67, Folder 1376)
  - Andrew Gibson, et al.: papers (Lg 28), 1776 (Box 67, Folder 1377)
  - Court of Session cases (Lg 29), 1776-77 (Box 67, Folder 1378)
  - Alexander Macewan: Information (Lg 30), 1776-77 (Box 67, Folder 1379)
  - Wylie v. Cuming: fragment (Lg 30.8), 1776 (Box 67, Folder 1379)
  - John Philip: papers (Lg 31), [1777] (Box 67, Folder 1379)
  - Court of Session cases (Lg 32), 1777-78 (Box 67, Folder 1380)
  - Campbell's Trustees v. Scotland: papers (Lg 34), 1778 (Box 67, Folder 1381)
  - John Chiesley: Trial (Lg 35), n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1381)
  - Craufurd v. Gemmill: papers (Lg 36), 1780-81 (Box 67, Folder 1382)
  - Craufurd v. Renny: papers (Lg 37), 1780-81 (Box 67, Folder 1383)
  - Patrick Douglas v. Earl of Dumfries: Petition (Lg 37.8), 1781 (Box 67, Folder 1383)
  - "McJerrow's Estate" (Lg 39), n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1384)
  - Legal notebook (Lg 40), 1786-87 (Box 68, Folder 1385)
  - "English fees" (Lg 41), 1786-88 (Box 68, Folder 1386)
  - Dilly v. Salte (Lg 42) (Box 68, Folder 1386)
  - "Carlisle election, 1786" (Lg 43) (Box 68, Folder 1386)
  - Carlisle: extracts from the Corporation Books, 1687-1777 (Lg 44), 1786 (Box 68, Folder 1387)
  - Essex Sessions: notes (Lg 45), 1786? (Box 68, Folder 1387)
  - Stubbs and Fynmore: general retainer (Lg 46), 1787 (Box 68, Folder 1388)
  - "Carlisle Committee" (Lg 47), 1787 (Box 68, Folder 1388)
  - Essex Midsummer Sessions (Lg 48), 1787 (Box 68, Folder 1388)
  - Essez Michaelmas Sessions (Lg 49), 1787 (Box 68, Folder 1389)
  - Whitefoord v. Whitefoord: Boswell's speech (Lg 50), 1788 (Box 68, Folder 1389)
  - "Appellant's Bill of Costs" (Lg 51), 1788 (Box 68, Folder 1389)
  - Arbitration in a process for scandal at Ochiltree (Lg 52), 1788? (Box 68, Folder 1390)
  - Address as Recorder...at Carlisle (Lg 53), 1788 (Box 68, Folder 1390)
  - Thomas Norman et al. v. Lonsdale, Boswell, et al.: Notice of prosecution (Lg 54), 1788 (Box 68, Folder 1391)
  - Summons (Lg 55), 1788 (Box 68, Folder 1391)
  - "Opinion on the case of Mrs. Mary Robbins" (Lg 56), 1790 (Box 68, Folder 1392)
  - Carlisle election: notice prohibiting chairing (Lg 57), 1790 (Box 68, Folder 1392)
  - Robert James: Information against (Lg 58), 1790 (Box 68, Folder 1392)
  - Thomas Norman: Information against (Lg 59), 1790? (Box 68, Folder 1392)
  - Thomas Head: Information against (Lg 59.1), 1790 (Box 68, Folder 1393)
  - Mary Fitzgerald: notes on a divorce (Lg 60), 1790? (Box 68, Folder 1393)
  - "Opinion on the case of Mather against Cunnison et econtra" (Lg 61), 1790 (Box 68, Folder 1393)
  - "Home Circuit Summer 1791" (Lg 62) (Box 68, Folder 1394)
  - "Opinion on a case in bankruptcy" (Lg 63), 1791 (Box 68, Folder 1394)
  - Notes concerning the Weldon Enclosure Bill (Lg 65), 1792 (Box 68, Folder 1395)
  - "Essex Sessions Midsummer" (Lg 66), 1792 (Box 68, Folder 1396)
  - Essex Michaelmas Sessions (Lg 67), 1792 (Box 68, Folder 1396)
  - Opinion on Testimony to be given by James Gibb (Lg 68), 1793? (Box 68, Folder 1396)
  - Essex Epiphany Sessions (Lg 69), 1793 (Box 68, Folder 1397)
  - Essex Easter and Midsummer Sessions (Lg 70), 1793 (Box 68, Folder 1397)
  - Opinion on an Annuity Bond (Lg 71), 1794 (Box 68, Folder 1397)
  - Precognition relative to the supposed murder of Mungo Miller (Lg 72), 1794 (Box 68, Folder 1398-99)
  - Alexander v. Borthwick: Indictment (Lg 72.5), 1822 (Box 68, Folder 1400)
  - James Stuart: Trial (Lg 73), 1822 (Box 68, Folder 1401)
  - Robert Alexander: Letter to Sir J. Mackintosh.... (Lg 74), 1822 (Box 68, Folder 1402)
- Accounts and Financial Papers, 1733-1836; Series VII; 4; (6 boxes)
  Accounts and Financial Papers fill Boxes 69-70 of this series. James Boswell's personal transactions are listed alphabetically by subject or type of material. Papers of other individuals are listed alphabetically by name or subject. For further information, consult the galleys to the Catalogue.
  See also: Series XVII, Boxes 168-171.
  - Galleys (Box 69, Folder 1403)
  - Auchinleck (estate)
    - "Account of...Crop Stock" (A 1), [1749] (Box 69, Folder 1404)
    - "Copy, Inventory..." (A 2), 1782 (Box 69, Folder 1404)